BIO

Jonathan Berger is a designer, developer and technologist who has been active in the NYC technology community since 2005, helping to build products, teams, and events. He is an internationally sought speaker who talks about startups, technology, Lean, Agile, and design. As a consultant he's been on the team with almost 40 startups and enterprises in the past few years. As a startup founder he helped build one of the first online ecommerce fashion marketplaces. These days he's interested in finding ways to make designers' lives better.

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

VP Product, Thrive Global, NY, NY 2017

Guide practice and product among a portfolio of front- and back-end web software, apps for iOS, Android, Alexa, and others.

Consultant, NY, NY 2015-2016

Coached companies in design and agile, usually in moments of transition, to adapt their practices to the changing realities of their business and the market, while tying process changes to concrete outcomes and deliverables. Clients include Vive (beauty), WiredScore & WiredConcierge (telecom), 2U (ed-tech), and Alpha (UX & product design enablement).

Associate Director of Product Design, Pivotal Labs, NY, NY 2008-2015

Led a team of ~10 designers, building an agile design practice and methodology.

Built web and mobile applications using Agile, XP, and Test-Driven methodologies.

Every day I'd code, design, anchor teams, lead inceptions, manage reports, and help run the office.

At Pivotal I've also been a Designer, Engineering Manager, and Design Manager.

Co-founder, Market Publique, Brooklyn, NY 2008-2013

Helped design and build an online vintage fashion marketplace, helping people buy and sell vintage clothes and build community around fashion. Launched at SxSW in 2008.

Founder, Publique Domain, Brooklyn, NY 2008-2009

Spun a product design studio off of Market Publique, working with clients like Spot.Us, the Anti-Defamation League, and NewsTrust.

SKILLS

Expert in Agile, Lean Startup, and Extreme Programming (XP) methodologies.

Experienced product designer (desktop and mobile), with a strong emphasis on User Experience (UX).

Experienced with modern web development tools including Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, (including frameworks

Rails, React, Node, Express, SASS, and many more) and shell scripting.

Extremely high level of proficiency in Vim, Adobe Creative Suite, AfterEffects, Final Cut Studio.

Extensive photography, and videography production and post-production experience for broadcast and internet. Adobe Certified Expert in Photoshop.

EDUCATION

New School University, NY, NY
Master of Arts in Media Studies, 2007
Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY
Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, 2001

PUBLIC SPEAKING, REFERENCES, & CODE.

Portfolio of talks at http://www.jonathanpberger.com/talks, writings at jonathanpberger.com/blog, and references & portfolio available upon request. Code lives at http://github.com/jonathanpberger.